Florence Jones

florence.jones99@icloud.com +447942617720

Portfolio: https://florencejones.netlify.app/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/florence-emily-jones/

Energy Reporter on the GlobalData Graduate Scheme writing with a sustainability and human rights focus. Covering the energy transition, mining, oil and gas and energy policy. Proven ability to write engaging and informative articles, and to conduct in-depth research and interviews.

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2023 - Present

Energy reporter - GlobalData

Daily news and feature writing including breaking news for a variety of industry-led publications averaging a total of 26,000 daily readers. My recent work exploring geopolitical issues around lithium deposits has climbed to one of the most-read across the platform historically. Extensive interview and research experience for original stories. Website, newsletter and digimag publication.

Oct 2022 - March 2023

Journalism Intern - The Borgen Project

Working in a global non-profit reporting on international stories with a focus on global poverty. Writing stories and long-form content for an online platform averaging over 100,000 monthly visits.

2021

Volunteer - New Union

Media work on the Open Data for All/ Offene Daten Fur Alle Project. Working to increase the accessibility of oparen data projects for the third sector. Collaboration between UK agency New Union and the Bertelsmann Stiftung's Smart Country project in Germany.

2020 - 2021

Editor - ECCE HOMO MAGAZINE

Editing content and coordination of contributors for Ecce Homo magazine, which explores contemporary societal questions in novel interdisciplinary ways.

2020

Social Media Coordinator - Hest Bank Dental Care

Single-handedly managed the business' social media informed by analytics. Grew social media followers by 64% over the course of 5 months.

2017 - 2021

Newswriter - Redbrick news

Weekly news stories Research, conducting interviews and pitching stories to editors.

EDUCATION

2021-2022

University of St Andrews, UK — MLitt Global, Social and Political Thought

Distinction

International Intellectual History and Political Theory including indigenous thought.

2017-2021

University of Birmingham, UK — Liberal Arts and Natural Sciences

First Class Honors

Major: French. Minors: Russian, International Relations, Global Politics, Interdisciplinary Research.

2019-2020 Year abroad - Universite Laval, Quebec, Canada

First Class Modules in Russian and Philosophy taught entirely in French.

2019 St Petersburg Higher School of Economics, St Petersburg, Russia

SKILLS

- Digital CMS and SEO optimisation.
- Languages: French (fluent), Russian (intermediate), German (intermediate)
- Digital literacy and ability to use data analysing programs and programming.(Microsoft Office, Datawrapper, Rstudio, Python)

AWARDS

- St. Andrews Dean's list for academic excellence (2022)
- University of Birmingham Valedictorian award for graduating cohort(2021)
- Redbrick news best reporter (2019)
- Head Girl QES Kirby Lonsdale(2017)

REFERENCES

- JP Casey, Editor, Globaldata: JP.Casey@verdict.co.uk
- Dr Margarita Vaysman, Personal Tutor, University of St Andrews: mv37@st-andrews.ac.uk
- Dr Simon Scott, Personal Tutor, University of Birmingham: s.scott@bham.ac.uk